Finding Aid for Washtenaw County Medical Society records, 1866-1966
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Washtenaw County Medical Society records 1866-1966
Washtenaw County Medical Society (Mich.)
4 linear feet
85546 Bf 2
Component county medical society of the Michigan State Medical Society; organizational files and minutes of meetings.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the Society (donor no. 4184 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Washtenaw County Medical Society, established in 1866, is a component county medical society of the Michigan State Medical Society. Its purpose is to bring together the physicians of Washtenaw County into one organization, to maintain a program of educational service to the public on matters of health and hygiene, to encourage an exchange of views among physicians, and to maintain a program of scientific education.
The record group includes organizational records, minutes of meetings, reports, correspondence, and miscellaneous subject files.
Subjects:
Medicine--Michigan--Washtenaw County--Societies, etc.; Washtenaw County Medical Society (Mich.)
- Organizational files
  - Undated and 1924-1946, 23 folders (Box 1)
  - 1947-1956, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - 1957-1966, 10 folders (Box 3)
- Other records and files
  - Ann Arbor Association of Physicians -- Ethics (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1907-1921, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Fee bills, 1867 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous case reports (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan Hygiene Laboratory reports on water, 1907-1910 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous reports and receipts, 1890-1912 (Box 3)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1866-1931 (Box 4)
    - 1866-1883
      (include constitution and by-laws)
    - 1911-1931 (Box 4)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors record book, 1903-1926 (Box 4)
  - Published material (Box 4)